Guide to the Charles G. Muller papers, 1914-1986
Muller, Charles G. papers, 1914-1986
- Series V. Writing Jobs
  - Fund raising (also, books and articles)
    - Reports on shopping Experience for RCA Manufacturing Company, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Verbatim Reports of Special Field Investigation for U.S. Envelope Company (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Shears Furniture Record (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Field Survey for Dixie Vortex Co. (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Report of Survey of Liquor Merchandising for Hiram Walker & Sons (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Survey for International Association of Milk Dealers, Scripts for blackouts Given at the Convention of the International Association of Milk Dealers, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - "A Home for the Liberal Ideal" (Brown University) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "A Ten-Year Development Program for a Great Community University" (University of Louisville) (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "The Danger Point" ? script for Public Health Committee of the Cup & Container Institute (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - AudiVision Scenario No. 1 entitled "Trapping for Profits" for Animal Trap Company of America (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Books, articles, radio script manuscripts
    - Cornell Frosh (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Knights of the Road (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Ship A-Hoyden (Box 16, Folder 23-24)
    - Shipwrecked on Mystery Island (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
    - The Commodore (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Fiction (adult) Published (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Laziest Man on the Campus (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Tigers of the Sea (Box 17, Folder 10-12)
    - The Baseball Detective (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Curry was Right (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - "Puck Chasers" (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Footloose and War Articles (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Unburied Treasure; "The Ellen Stories" printed in "The American Girl" (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Hardcover and Paperback
    - General Articles (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Business Articles (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Turk" stories (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Eve and Sailing Stories (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "Bim" Stories (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "Association Men" (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Printers? Ink Monthly" (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Serials:, "Puck Chasers"; "Third Base Detective"; "Lee Rails Awash"; "tigers of the Sea" (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "Fabulous Potomac Passage" from U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "The Hat Trick" from Adventure Bound (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "Basketball Forward" from Let?s Read (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Curry was Right (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - The Baseball Detectives (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Puck Chasers Incorporated (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - The Darkest Day: 1814 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Bloody Sundown (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Unburied Treasure, 1944 (Box 18)
    - Tigers of the Sea, 1946 (Box 18)
    - Ship A-Hoyden, 1946 (Box 18)
    - The Proudest Day, 1960 (Box 18)
- Series VI. Miscellany
  - Correspondence
    - Work leads 1965-1972 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Work leads 1965-1972, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - "Letters from interesting people". Publishers, Cornellians, editors (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Letters from interesting people". and friends (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - "Letters from interesting people" (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Autographs
    - Includes David Lavender, Marshall Sprague (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Charles G. Muller Biographical Material
    - Sailing plaque and photographs (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Photographs, letters from publishers, biographical sketches for reference books and copy of birth certificate (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Alphabetical correspondence, 1926-1985
    - A (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Bristow (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Boger Asay, Rebecca Davis (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - B (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Butler, Ellis Parker (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - C (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Conroy, John (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Cornell University correspondence (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Cornell Library Associates (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - D-E (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - de Fur, Paul (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Diamant (Berke), Anita (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Eaton, Chris (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Elsas, Norman (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - F-H (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Folwell (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Greenberg (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Hanson, Josephine (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Hastings, Alan (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Holly (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Hudson - Drey (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - I-J (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Jon Jessup (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Jewett, George (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - K-L (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Langdon, Charles (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Lerocher, Fred (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Lynces, Tony (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - M (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Marcelle (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Marion (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Mazet, Horace (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Meyer, Phil (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Morland, Fred (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Morrissey, Sally (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Muller, Jenny (Coons) (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - N (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - O-Q (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Olson, Howard and Helen (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Peterson, Maureen (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - R (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Rankin, Victor and Gladys (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Raymond, Mary (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Rey, Jim and Sharon (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Roden, Henry Wisdom (Tex) and Leslie (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Rooney, Patrick and Grace (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - S (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Sampson (Marshall), Marian (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Scofield, Dorothy (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Scully, Michael (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Soule (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Stanley, Paul Leatherman (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Strunk, William (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - T (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Taylor, Morrie (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - Tregelles, Chris (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - U-V (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - Vail, Malcolm (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - W-Z (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - E. B. White (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - Unknown (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - Work leads (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - Graef, Edward: "On the Solution of Three Ancient Problems" (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Book jackets (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Publications and writing materials
    - Bloody Sunday (Box 12, Folder 1-4)
    - A Cry for Help (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Darkest Day paperback (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Hero of Two Seas (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - No Cork for the Bottle (Box 12, Folder 8-10)
    - Kotler ? Cork TV movie (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - People are Wonderful ? Faustina Orner (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - People (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - The Proudest Day (Box 12, Folder 14-16)
    - Proudest Day paperback (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - "So Proudly!" (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - When the Rocks Talked ? action, plot, characters (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - For Rocks ? Part 1 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - "Boys? and Girls? Newspaper" ? correspondence from readers (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper subscriptions, misc. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - "Newspaper" editorial requirements, inventory, correspondence with contributors (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Clippings, etc. promoting "Newspaper" (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence concerning first issue(s) of "Newspaper" (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - "Newspaper" correspondence (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - "Newspaper" ? pre-publication, promo, post-publication, description (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - "Newspaper" correspondence (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Four Corners Magazine (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Four Corners notes? (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - "From a Window on Libau," 1921 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - In the San Juan ? Sketches by Rev. J.J. Gibbons (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Postal cards (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Mines (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Towns (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Color (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Glossary (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Rail building material (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Characters (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Stockton/Eskridge (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Newsclippings (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Flora - Fauna (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "The Boys? and Girls? Newspaper" ? 2 issues (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - First flight cover of the Pan American Clipper, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Ideas, quotes, books to read, music to get (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Names (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Nil Desperandum - Babs (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Personal (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Purgatory (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Strater (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Story ideas (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Motion pictures/TV (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Book publishers (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Plotting (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Stories for Barbara/Hair (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Book idea (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Copyrights (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Copies of Grandfather stories (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Mother (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Personal
    - Muller records, birth certificates and other (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Muller passports and other (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Muller family (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Jeff?s visa and tax info (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Letters to home (George Muller, 932 6th Ave., New York, NY) from Muller, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Letters, 1932-33, no date (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Alaska (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Book ideas (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Contemporary authors (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Cornell University (Box 13, Folder 28-32)
    - Cornell Class of 1918 (Box 13, Folder 33-34)
    - Cornell University (Box 13, Folder 35-36)
    - Durango (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - General semantics (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Library (Durango) (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Mensa (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - The Orvis Company (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Odds (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Overseas Press Club (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Silva Mind control (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Sleep (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Union Trust (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
    - Western trip (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Wyoming Archives (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - AARP insurance (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Blue Cross/Blue Shield (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Chiefs of police (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Community activities (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Community activities ? Great Marsh (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Elderly Commission (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Eyes - aphasic (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Eyes (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Hernia ? Genvert, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Hernia, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Medicare (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Medicare forms (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Prostate ? tumor, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Speech therapy, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Social Security/GNYF (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Seton Hospital, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Stroke, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Yoga (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - File cards ? names and addresses of book writers, agencies, etc. (Box 19)
    - 1 folder, not described (Map-case A-8)
  - Real estate and miscellany
    - Westport (Ct.) house (Box 14, Folder 25-27)
    - House rental, Winter 1980 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - House rental, de Lauro, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - 1978 rental (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - House, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - House ? guaranties, contracts, credit cards (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - House - suppliers (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - House miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - House painting (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - House ? ideas to buy, to do (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - House ? floor plans, picture (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Insurance (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Jim Morehart ? General Motors (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Homeowner?s flood insurance (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Lawn (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Rowland property (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Zenith TV (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Insurance (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Westport assessor (Box 14, Folder 45)